davis allen

software engineer

ABOUT

I'm a software engineer with a background in game design and project management. After this spell in games, I decided to return full-time to Software Engineering, returning to university to earn my Master's.

I bring solid technical chops and good design sensibilities to bear on the task of building engaging, compelling and fun experiences, in code.

I can work through the entire product lifecycle, from initial conception and prototyping to implementation, through to delivery and deployment. I love turning deep, complex systems into simple, elegant, intuitive experiences. If it puts a smile on someone's face or makes someone's life easier, I will enjoy building it.

SKILLS

Languages

- Java, Javascript, Python, Ruby, C#, C++
- HTML, CSS, SQL

Frameworks, etc.

- Spring, Rails, keras
- Unity + Unreal Game Engines
- Arduino (Processing)
- Agile dev methodologies / project management

CONTACT

973.747.4916 davis@davisallen.com davisallen.com github.com/Davis-B-Allen linkedin.com/in/davisallen/

SELECTED EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Freelance / 2017 to Present

- Worked on several dynamic web applications (mostly Ruby, Rails, JS)
- Prototyped game design and web utilities for educational games

Game Designer / Producer

bMuse, LLC / 2012 to 2016

- Led Game Design and Production on a variety of mobile games and connected toy projects
- Drove product development, from early-stage prototyping through the full product development cycle
- Sample of titles shipped: Transformers: Battlemasters, Hess Tractor Trek, Nerf Cyberhoop

Full-Stack Developer

YouAre.TV / 2010 to 2012

- Worked as a full-stack developer on two web projects at NY-based startup: a college-exclusive social network and a real-time streaming video / interactive television platform.
- Worked primarily with Ruby on Rails, Postgresql, Javascript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Flash / Flex 4, Node.js, socket.io, Wowza Media Server

SELECTED/RECENT PROJECTS

scandit

a reddit clone built with spring boot, employing a microservices architecture (source on Github)

- Java, Spring, PostgreSQL, Javascript

tweet analyzer

sentiment analysis project using deep learning to classify sentiment of tweets (source on Github)

- python, tensorflow, keras

EDUCATION

CUNY, Hunter College

Master's, Computer Science, 2018 to Present

- Completed all coursework; GPA: 4.0
- Currently completing Master's project; Expected Graduation: 2020

General Assembly

Java Development Academy, 2019

- Full-time, immersive, 11-week bootcamp; Java, Spring, Javascript

McGill University

Bachelor's, Physics, 2006-2010